SEVDE UYLAS

♦ AUSTIN, TX 512-537-4422

o DETAILS o

Austin, TX 512-537-4422 ssevdeuylas@gmail.com

o LINKS o

https://github.com/ShChloe

o SKILLS o

Data Analysis

Data Visualization

SQL

Python

Tableau

Machine Learning

Pandas

Stata

IBM SPSS Statistics

SPSS/R

Machine Learning

ETL/HTML/CSS/Bootstrap

Flask

Javascript

PROFILE

Developing professional experience in combining my expertise in applied statistics as well as social sciences to be a multidisciplinary Data Analyst; collecting, cleaning, analyzing, and making predictions and conclusions out of the data with the best tools available.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Data Analiyst at University of Texas, Austin,TX

May 2019 — Present

Collecting and cleaning large data sets with Python, utilizing data sets with SQL, SQLite, sqlalchemy, MongoDB. Making API calls with Python, automating web scraping, using Beautiful Soup, Flask App. Creating Front End web apps with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, D3.js, Leaflet.js, Plotly.js Building web applications using Python, JavaScript, APIs -Assessing data using VBA, Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, R, SQL. Using business intelligent software such as Tableau for presentations and reporting. Discovering machine learning models with linear regression, k-nearest, neural network, decision trees, support vector machine.

Ph.D. Student at Dalhouse University, Halifax, CA

September 2017 — Present

Attending Quantitative Analysis classes for two terms. Using STATA to clean, mining and analyzing data for research projects. Presenting reports.

Administrative Assistant at VisoVita Media Production Company, New York, NY

April 2017 — August 2017

Representing the brand in meetings, making translations from Turkish during presentations. Identifying and communicating with possible clients through market research.

Research Assistance at Fatih University, Istanbul,TR

June 2013 — December 2016

Conducting literature reviews about various research projects. Managing research groups.

Collecting thousands of data from several cities. Analyzing both qualitative and quantitative data.

Utilizing SPSS in analyzing data for the projects and a master thesis and reporting. Presenting conclusions in international conferences.

EDUCATION

Data Analysis and Visualization Program, The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, TX

May 2019 — Present

Ph.D. Student, Sociology, Dalhousie University, Halifax, CA

September 2017 — Present

M.A, Sociology, Fatih University, Istanbul,TR

December 2015 — June 2016